Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office. Wilfried Henkel Papers, 1957-1987, bulk 1975-1984 RL.00697
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office. Wilfried Henkel papers
1957-1987, bulk 1975-1984
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office
RL.00697
13.5 Linear Feet
12,150 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In addition, all or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office. Wilfried Henkel Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1995.
Biographical Note
Chronology
1927 July 23 Born
1950s Studied German Language and Literature and History at the University of Marburg
1955-1959 Worked as junior editor of a family-type magazine
1959 May 1 Began work for JWT Frankfurt as a copy-writer
1960 Creative Group Head; worked on S.C. Johnson account (launch of Pronto, etc.)
1968-1970 Creative Director, JWT Frankfurt; responsible for the Target Plan
1971 July 6 Director, JWT Frankfurt, deputy to George Black; responsible (with him) for design department (Gestaltungs-Abteilung) and assisting in organizational and personnel matters
1974 Unit Leader, JWT Frankfurt (clients included Ford, Braun, Kellogg's, Dunlop, BBC, Chevron, Hoffmanns, Pepsi, Unilever)
1977 Geschäftsführer/Managing Director and member of the Board of Directors; responsible for clients Deutsche Bank, Stabilisierungsfond Deutscher Wein, Commodore Computer, TEFAL and new business presentations
1987 Left JWT on July 31
Collection Overview
The papers of Wilfried Henkel, former managing director (Geschäftsführer) at the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT), Frankfurt office, span the years 1957 to 1987, with the bulk of the material dating from 1975 to 1984. The collection consists of articles and presentations (typed or offprints) accompanied by charts and graphs, typed and handwritten correspondence, external and internal memoranda, as well as press clippings and other printed material, and documents Henkel's activities during his tenure at the Frankfurt office, where he was considered the chief ideologist. Throughout his time in Frankfurt, Henkel worked on individual accounts, but more importantly he was one of the early proponents of corporate advertising, especially in the form of corporate identity and corporate communications. In addition, he worked extensively on JWT's corporate strategy, the T-Plan (target plan).
Specific topics documented in the Wilfried Henkel papers include the philosophy of advertising as evidenced in particular (mostly German) advertising campaigns; analyses of agencies', businessmen's, and customers' attitudes toward advertising; JWT's corporate philosophy as presented in the T-Plan; presentations on the future of advertising; and individual advertising campaigns--including Deutsche Bank, Deutscher Wein, Fichtel and Sachs, Flachglas, Ford Motor Company, Frankfurter Hypothekenbank, Hercules, and Zanders--supervised by Henkel for JWT. While the general files in the Henkel papers document communication between JWT and its clients as well as within JWT, other parts of the collection contain a high percentage of presentations and talks.
Approximately 70% of the collection is in German. Only correspondence with foreign offices and clients, as well as some of the subject material, is in English. The collection is arranged into five series--the General Files Series, the Client Files Series, the New Business Presentations Series, the Subject Files Series, and the Writings and Speeches Series.
The General Files Series documents the day-to-day activities and proceedings in the JWT Frankfurt Office during Henkel's tenure. Most significantly, this series contains Henkel's domestic and foreign correspondence, house memoranda, and internal as well as client reports. Topics include the acquisition and loss of clients (especially Ford); JWT's position in the German advertising industry; organization and administration within JWT Frankfurt (especially internal finances and work in units); the celebration of 30 years of JWT in Frankfurt; the founding of subsidiaries Deltakos; JWT Direct; and Pro:Motion; and the opening of the Düsseldorf and Hamburg offices of JWT.
The Client Files Series reflects Henkel's involvement in the planning and financial aspects of JWT-Frankfurt's relationship with its clients. Most of the series documents the on-going planning and execution of advertising campaigns--through correspondence, presentations, and briefings--as well as general and economic relations between JWT-Frankfurt and its clients. The major accounts in this series include Braun, Commodore, Deutsche Bank, Deutscher Wein, Fichtel and Sachs, Flachglas, Ford Motor Company, Frankfurter Hypothekenbank, Hercules, Knauf, Kraft, PEP, and Zanders. One item of particular interest is the presentation made by JWT Frankfurt to Ford in 1985 in an unsuccessful attempt to keep the Ford account. For several clients--including Braun, Deutsche Bank, Ford and Zanders--Henkel supervised a corporate identity campaign. The files of several accounts also collect press clippings relevant to the client.
The New Business Presentations Series provides information on JWT-Frankfurt's efforts to win new clients or additional accounts. The material on any given presentation usually includes internal correspondence suggesting a new client or account, internal evaluations of that suggestion, first contacts with the prospective client, JWT's preparation for the presentation, the presentation itself, and a subsequent analysis of the company presentation and memoranda (Haus-Mitteilungen) on the success of the presentation and the likelihood of getting the account. These files include a small number of clients which were actually won (e.g., Frankfurter Hypothekenbank), but mostly cover companies which chose other agencies. In some cases, there was direct competition between the various companies to whom JWT was presenting, such as between the department stores, Hertie, Kaufhof, and Karstadt. Well-documented clients include Bridgestone, Hertie, and Philips.
The Subject Files Series, the centerpiece of the Henkel collection, covers a variety of topics related to the development and application of JWT's T-Plan: the concept of corporate identity and the idea of corporate communication. In addition, this series contains Henkel's collection of background material on the subject of consumerism. As chief ideologist of JWT's Frankfurt office in the 1970s and early 1980s, Henkel was especially involved in these areas. There are a number of different versions of JWT's T-Plan from between 1970 and 1982. Each of the individual topics contains articles and presentations pertaining to its theory, examples of its practice at JWT and in the advertising business at large, as well as research on the topic. Henkel participated in the discussion through presentations such as his frequently revised "Corporate Identity--Mehr Marktanteil im Bewußtsein der Öffentlichkeit" ( Corporate Identity--A Greater Share of the Market in the Public Consciousness) found in Corporate Identity/Presentations/Henkel Lecture 1977-78.
The Writings and Speeches Series collects works by Henkel as well as a number of outsiders to the company. While many articles, presentations, and talks come with author names, there is also a significant number of anonymous contributions. The topics of the writings range from philosophical examinations of particular aspects of advertising to comments on individual advertising campaigns. About half of the articles are in German, the rest in English.
Related materials may also be found in other collections from the J. Walter Thompson Company Frankfurt Office.
Clippings (information artifacts); Advertising -- Management; Advertising executives; Advertising agencies -- Germany; Advertising agencies -- History; Corporations -- Public relations -- Germany; Corporate image -- Germany; Marketing -- Germany; Advertising -- History; Advertising agencies; Consumers -- Attitudes; Zanders Feinpapiere AG; J. Walter Thompson Company; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office; J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office; Henkel, Wilfried; Hercules (Firm); Frankfurter Hypothekenbank (Firm); Ford Motor Company; Flachglas AG; Fichter and Sachs (Firm); Deutscher Wein (Firm); Deutsche Bank
- General Files Series, 1971-1987
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains typed and hand-written letters, telexes and telegrams, printed material, notes, memoranda, clippings and articles, minutes, reports, charts and graphs, questionnaires, receipts, contracts, and other documents concerning JWT Frankfurt. Documents chiefly Henkel's communication with staff in management, with other JWT offices in foreign correspondence, and with his co-workers through memoranda. Includes his domestic correspondence with the public as well as memoranda and reports concerning a variety of subjects. Arranged alphabetically by type of record, thereunder chronologically.
  See further item level description for this series in the inventory file in Research Services or in the Word document at F:\Specoll\Technical Services Department\Finding Aids\Word Files Created from Web\Henkel, Wilfried.doc.
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Domestic, 1972-1973, 1975, 1981-1986, 8 folders (Box 1)
    - Foreign, 1972-1973, 1975-1977, 1982-1986, 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Düsseldorf and Hamburg, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Electronic Data Processing (EDV), 1984 (Box 1)
  - Internal Finances, 1973, 1975, 1985-1986, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Job Ads, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Job Applications
    - Alphabetical A-Z, 1971-1980, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Free lance, 1971-1980 (Box 1)
  - JWT Direct, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Market Research, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Memoranda
    - 1972, Group Head Meetings (Box 1)
    - 1972-1973, Organization (Box 1)
    - 1973, Quadrovirate (Box 1)
    - 1975-1977, 1981-1986, 6 folders (Box 1)
    - 1984-1986, Organization (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1972-1973, 1975-1977, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1983-1987 (Box 2)
  - Personnel, 1972-1986, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Press Clippings, 1971-1975 (Box 2)
  - Pro:Motion [subsidiary], 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - Reports, 1975-1977, 1983-1986, 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Seminars and Meetings
    - 1975-1977 (Box 2)
    - Schotten [location], 1979-1980
      - Core group (Box 2)
      - Efficiency (Box 2)
      - General (Box 2)
    - EMM [European Managers' Meeting], 1983
      - Correspondence (Box 2)
      - English material (Box 2)
      - Background material (Box 2)
  - View-Data (Btx) 1984 (Box 2)
- Client Files Series, 1970-1987
  Typed and handwritten domestic and foreign correspondence, telexes, notes, ad copy, contracts, memoranda (Haus-Mitteilungen), presentations and briefings, reports (Kontaktberichte), and research concerning the accounts with which Henkel was involved. Organized alphabetically by client for the major accounts, followed by a brief series of various clients. Within each account, the files are divided by topic (thereunder chronologically). Additional materials relating to the Ford Motor Company, which were discovered after processing of the collection had been completed, are listed here but are physically located at the end of the collection, and may be found in boxes 11-12.
  - Braun (Box 2)
    - Ad Copy, 1975-1977 (Box 2)
    - Contact Reports, 1975-1977 (Box 2)
    - Corporate Identity, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 2)
    - Memoranda, 1975-1978 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1975-1977 (Box 2)
  - Commodore
    - Ad Copy, 1984-1985 (Box 2)
    - Contract, 1982-1984 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 2)
    - International, 1983 (Box 2)
  - International, 1984-1985 (Box 3)
    - Memoranda, 1983-1986 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1983-1986 (Box 3)
    - Presentations and Briefings, 1983-1985 (Box 3)
  - Deutsche Bank
    - 100 Years
      - Background Material, 1986 (Box 3)
      - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Ad Copy, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Corporate Campaign, 1983-1985 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1985, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Job Search, 1984 (Box 3)
    - Memoranda, 1981-1985, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1976-1978, 1981-1985, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Presentations and Briefings, 1981-1985, 6 folders (Box 3)
    - Press Clippings, 1981-1985 (Box 3)
    - Reports, 1981-1985 (Box 3)
    - Seminars
      - - Grasellenbach, 1984
        - Königstein
          - Organization, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
          - Presentations, 1983 (Box 3)
      - - Kronberg, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Deutscher Wein (Box 4)
    - Ad Copy, 1983-1987 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1987, 5 folders (Box 4)
    - Memoranda, 1983-1987, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1977, 1983-1987, 6 folders (Box 4)
    - Presentations and Briefings, 1984-1987, 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Reports, 1982-1987, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Fella
    - Ad Copy, 1976 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 4)
    - Memoranda, 1976 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
    - Presentations, 1976 (Box 4)
    - Reports, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Fichtel and Sachs
    - Ad Copy, 1976-1977, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Background Material, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
    - Memoranda, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
    - Presentations and Briefings, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
    - Reports, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
    - Research, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - Flachglas
    - Correspondence, 1981-1986 (Box 4)
    - Memoranda, 1982-1985 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1982-1984 (Box 4)
    - Presentations and Briefings, 1982 (Box 4)
    - Press Clippings, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
    - Reports, 1982-1985 (Box 4)
    - Research, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Ford
    - Ad Copy
      - Capri, 1971, 1977, 2 folders (Box 5)
      - Consul, 1970-1971 (Box 5)
      - Escort, 1977 (Box 5)
      - Eva, 1977 (Box 5)
      - Fiesta, 1977 (Box 5)
      - Granada, 1970-1971, 1977, 2 folders (Box 5)
      - MH Project, 1970-1971 (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous, 1977 (Box 5)
      - Taunus, 1977 (Box 5)
      - Trade Pamphlet, 1971 (Box 5)
      - Transit, 1971, 1977, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Briefings, 1977-1978, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Car Orders, 1975-1983 (Box 5)
    - Corporate Identity
      - Ad Copy, 1981-1982 (Box 5)
      - Background Material, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
      - Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
      - Presentations and Briefings, 1981 (Box 5)
      - Research, 1981 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence
      - Domestic, 1977-1978, 1983-1987, 3 folders (Box 5)
      - Foreign, 1973-1975, 1977-1978, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Memoranda, 1977-1978, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1976-1978, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Monthly Reports
      - Advertising, 1977-1978, 3 folders (Box 5)
      - New Registrations, 1977-1978, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Presentations, 1977-1978, 1984-1986, 5 folders (Box 6)
      - Preparation
        - - English, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
        - - German, 1985-1986, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Press Clippings, 1974-1975, 1977-1978, 1983-1986, 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Reports, 1977-1978, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Research, 1974-1975 (Box 6)
  - Frankfurter Hypothekenbank
    - Ad Copy, 1985-1986, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1986, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Finances
      - Budget, 1985-1986, 3 folders (Box 6)
      - Client Bills, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
      - Estimates, 1985-1986, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Media, 1985 (Box 6)
    - Memoranda, 1985-1986 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1985 Jan. - June (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1985 Jul. - Dec. (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1986 (Box 7)
    - Press Clippings, 1985-1986 (Box 7)
    - Reports, 1985-1986, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Research, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Trade Mark Registration, 1985-1986, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Hercules
    - Ad Copy, 1976-1977 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 7)
    - Memoranda, 1976-1977 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1974-1977 (Box 7)
    - Presentations and Briefings, 1976-1977, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Press Clippings, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Reports, 1976-1977 (Box 7)
  - Johnson Wax
    - Ad Copy, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Background Material, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1985 (Box 7)
    - Memoranda, 1976-1977 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1976-1977 (Box 7)
    - Reports, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Knauf
    - Ad Copy, 1976-1977 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 7)
    - Memoranda, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Presentations, 1976 (Box 7)
    - Reports, 1976 (Box 7)
  - Kraft
    - Cheese Umbrella
      - Ad Copy, 1981 (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous, 1981 (Box 7)
      - Presentations and Briefings, 1981-1982 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1985 (Box 7)
  - PEP
    - Ad Copy, 1982 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1981 (Box 7)
    - Presentations and Briefings, 1981 (Box 7)
    - Reports, 1981-1982 (Box 7)
  - Zanders
    - Ad Copy, 1983-1985 (Box 7)
    - Annual Report, 1983-1984 (Box 7)
    - Corporate Communication, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
    - Corporate Image, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1985 (Box 7)
    - Finances, 1983-1984 (Box 7)
    - Media, 1983-1984 (Box 7)
    - Memoranda, 1983-1984 (Box 7)
    - Press Clippings, 1983-1984 (Box 7)
    - Reports, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
  - Various Clients
    - A-C, 1974-1987 (Box 7)
    - De Beers, 1982-1986, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - E-H, 1974-1987 (Box 7)
    - Elida-Gibbs-Lever-Sunlicht, 1974-1976 (Box 7)
    - Elida-Gibbs-Lever-Sunlicht, 1977-1987, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - GEFA, 1984-1987 (Box 8)
    - IZE, 1981-1982 (Box 8)
    - Jacobs, 1975-1987 (Box 8)
    - L-P, 1974-1987 (Box 8)
    - R-W, 1974-1987 (Box 8)
    - Tefal, 1983-1987, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Wick, 1975-1987 (Box 8)
    - Background Material, 1982-1986, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Ford, 1975: Office Files, 7 folders (Box 11)
    - Correspondence (Box 11)
    - Briefings (Box 11)
    - Memoranda (Haus-Mitteilungen) (Box 11)
    - Contact Reports (KontactBerichte) (Box 11)
    - Minutes (Protokolle) (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Verschiedenes) (Box 11)
    - Monthly Reports (Box 11)
  - Presentations I (Präsentationen), 12 folders
    - Konzeption: Händler-Werks-Kampagne (Box 11)
    - Kommunikationsstrategie Ford H-Serie Escort RS (Box 11)
    - 1977 Bobcat Program Advertising Agency Briefing, 1975 May 21 (Box 11)
    - Ford Taunus (Box 11)
    - Was Wir Kommunizieren Wollen: Leitgedanken (Box 12)
    - Das Wichlitgste Aufeinen Blick: Ford Granada (Box 12)
    - New Ford Taunus (Box 12)
    - Einfünrung Taunus Escort 1975, 1974 Oct. 24 (Box 12)
    - Der Neue Ford Granada (Box 12)
    - Der Ford Taunus '75 (Box 12)
    - Die Vernünfltige Serienausstattung, 1974 Sept. 10 (Box 12)
    - Die Neue Ford Escort (Box 12)
  - Presentations II (Präsentationen), 9 folders
    - Überlegungen Zur Mediaplanung Für die Ford-Werbung 1976, 1975 Aug. (Box 12)
    - Bobcat Deutschland (Box 12)
    - Ford Taunus (Box 12)
    - Positionierungs-Überlegungen Taunus '76 ½ (Box 12)
    - 1976-½ Taunus Program (Box 12)
    - New Ford Taunus (Box 12)
    - Bobcat (Box 12)
    - Taunus (Box 12)
    - Ford-JWT Meeting, 1974 Mar. 11 (Box 12)
  - Reports (Texte), 3 folders
    - Capri-Taunus (Box 12)
    - Escort-Granada-Consul (Box 12)
    - LKW-Transit-Händler-Allgem-Bobcat (Box 12)
- New Business Presentation Files Series, 1974-1987
  Correspondence, reports, memoranda (Haus-Mitteilungen), reports (Kontaktberichte), market analysis drafts, notes, printed material, clippings and presentation material including photographs and storyboards. Arranged alphabetically by client's name, thereunder chronologically.
  - A, 1974-1987 (Box 8)
  - Apollo, 1977 (Box 8)
  - B, 1974-1987 (Box 8)
  - BASF, 1978-1986 (Box 8)
  - Bridgestone, 1978-1983 (Box 8)
  - C-G, 1974-1987, 5 folders (Box 8)
  - Gödecke, 1977-1978 (Box 8)
  - Gruppe 21, 1975-1977 (Box 8)
  - H, 1974-1987 (Box 8)
  - Hertie, 1974-1975 (Box 8)
  - I-P, 1974-1987, 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Philips, 1978-1983 (Box 9)
  - R-Z, 1974-1987, 5 folders (Box 9)
  - Uni-Cardan, 1977-1978 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1981-1987 (Box 9)
- Subject Files Series, 1957-1987
  Typed and annotated presentations and memos, photocopied articles, clippings from newspapers and journals, other materials involved in presentations (transparencies, flashcards), research reports, and typed and hand-written correspondence and telexes. Organized by overarching subject, thereunder by topical and formal subheadings, then chronological.
  - Consumerism (Box 9)
    - Agencies, 1957-1983 (Box 9)
    - Consumers, 1973-1983, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Counteradvertising, 1974-1976 (Box 9)
    - Criticism, 1974-1981 (Box 9)
    - Economy, 1974-1982, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - GWA, 1973-1977 (Box 9)
    - JWT, 1973-1975 (Box 9)
    - Management, 1974-1975, 1978-1983, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Marketing, 1975-1983 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1973-1983, 3 folders (Box 9)
    - New Media, 1980-1983 (Box 9)
    - Organization, 1974-1977 (Box 9)
    - Policy, 1974-1975 (Box 9)
    - Research, 1971-1983, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Rules of Competition, 1974-1980 (Box 9)
    - Sales Promotion, 1980-1982 (Box 9)
    - Theses, 1974-1981 (Box 9)
  - Corporate Communication
    - Philips, 1984-1985 (Box 9)
    - Zahnradfabrik, 1984-1985 (Box 10)
    - Zanders, 1981-1985 (Box 10)
  - Corporate Identity
    - Addresses, 1977 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence, 1977-1980 (Box 10)
    - Information
      - Background Material, 1976-1980 (Box 10)
      - Campaign
        - - English, 1969-1977 (Box 10)
        - - German, 1977-1982 (Box 10)
      - Management, 1976-1981 (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous, 1976-1980 (Box 10)
      - Research, 1977-1981 (Box 10)
      - Social Marketing, 1977-1978 (Box 10)
    - Panel Discussion
      - Correspondence, 1976-1978, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Organization, 1977 (Box 10)
      - Pamphlet, 1977 (Box 10)
      - Presentations, 1976-1977 (Box 10)
    - Presentations
      - Cases, 1977-1986 (Box 10)
      - Henkel Lecture, 1977-1978 (Box 10)
      - Karstadt, 1977-1980 (Box 10)
    - Press Clippings, 1976-1979 (Box 10)
    - Research, 1979-1987 (Box 10)
  - Publications
    - Mittwochsreport, 1975-1979, 5 folders (Box 10)
  - T-Plan
    - Annual Report, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Basisresearch, 1979-1980 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1982 (Box 10)
    - Documentation, 1972-1974 (Box 10)
    - Examples
      - A-Z, 1969-1982 (Box 10)
      - Campari; CD, 1980s (Box 10)
      - Ford, 1969-1980 (Box 10)
      - Korall; Lux, 1969-1980 (Box 10)
    - Presentations
      - English, 1973-1978 (Box 10)
      - German, 1970-1982, 4 folders (Box 11)
    - Press Clippings, 1971-1982
      - Kontakter, 1979 (Box 11)
- Writings and Speeches Files Series, 1972-1985
  Type-written and photocopied articles, talks, and presentations, occasionally annotated by the author or reader; also some offprints of articles. Organized by author (where known), thereunder chronologically.
  - Anonymous, 1972-1985, 5 folders (Box 11)
  - Basisresearch, 1975 (Box 11)
  - Henkel, 1974-1984 (Box 11)
  - Osierski, 1976-1978, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Schützendorf, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous A-Z, 1972-1985, 7 folders (Box 11)